Register of the Trotsky collection, 1917-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- LEON TROTSKY SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1907-1940. (Box 14-22)
  - Filmed speech, Copenhagen, 1932 November 25. Published in Writings, 1932 (New York, Mimeograph copy (in English), 1973). (Folder 45)
  - "On the Situation of the Left Opposition," 1932 December 16. Published in Bulletin international de l'Opposition Communiste de Gauche Typed copy (in English) (Folder 46)
  - "On Those Who Have Forgotten the ABC," 1932 December 28. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Communist League of America Typed copy (in English), (1933 January 28). (Folder 47)
  - "Pered resheniem," 1933 February 5. Published in Permanente Revolution Typescript (in Russian) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - "The United Front for Defense," 1933 February 23. Published in Unser Wort (1933 March). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in Spanish), entitled Que es el frente unico proletario? (Mexico City, 1977) (Folder 2)
  - Discussion with Arne Swabeck on the race question in the United States, Prinkipo, 1933 February 28. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Communist League of America Typed transcript (in German), and typed copy (in English), (1933 April 19). (Folder 3)
  - "Signal trevogi," 1933 March 3. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 4)
  - "On the Question of the Situation in the American League," 1933 March 7. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Communist League of America Typescript (in English), (1933 April 29). (Folder 5)
  - "Germany and the U.S.S.R.," 1933 March 17. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Communist League of America Typed copy (in English), (1933 March 31). (Folder 6)
  - "Selin i Puankare," 1933 May 10. Published in The Atlantic Monthly Typescript (in Russian), (1935 October). (Folder 7)
  - "Chto takoe natsional-sotsializm?" 1933 June 10. Published in Neue Weltbuhne Typescript (in Russian), (1933 July 13). (Folder 8)
  - "Fashizm i lozungi demokratii," 1933 July 14. Published in Unser Wort Typescript (in Russian), (1933 August). (Folder 9)
  - "Pered ot'ezdom," 1933 July 15. Published in Modern Monthly, (1934 March)
    - Typescripts (in Russian and English) (Folder 10)
    - Printed copy (in English, in Modern Monthly, 1934 March) (Folder 11)
  - "Nel'zia bol'she ostavat'sia v odnom 'Internatsionale' so Stalinym, Manuilskim, Lovozskim i ko.," 1933 July 20. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Communist League of America Mimeograph copy (in German), (1933 August). (Folder 12)
  - "Uspekh ili neudacha?" 1933 September 7. Published in Oeuvres, Volume II (Paris, Typescript (in Russian), 1978). (Folder 13)
  - "Klassovaia priroda sovetskogo gosudarstva," 1933 October 1. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii (1933 October). Typescript (in Russian); and printed copy in pamphlet form (in English), entitled The Class Nature of the Soviet State (London, 1973). Latter also includes English version of "Rabochee gosudarstvo, termidor i bonapartizm", (1935 February 1) (Folder 14)
  - "Chego khochet Gitler?" 1933 November 23. Published in Neue Weltbuhne Typescript (in Russian), (1933 November 30). (Folder 15)
  - "Politicheskii protsess bez politicheskoi osi," 1933 November 26. Published in Neue Weltbuhne Typescript (in Russian). Includes related letter by Maxim Lieber, (1933 December 14). (Folder 16)
  - "Natsionalizm i khoziaistvo," 1933 November 30. Published in Neue Weltbuhne Typescript (in Russian), (1933 December 28). (Folder 17)
  - "Zametki zhurnalistov," 1933 December 12. Published in La Verite Typescript (in Russian), (1933 December 22). (Folder 18)
  - Chetvertyi Internatsional i voina, Published in Geneva, 1934. Printed copy (in Russian, Geneva, 1934) (Folder 19)
  - "Anatolii Vasilevich Lunacharskii," 1934 January 1. Published in Neue Weltbuhne, Typescript (in English), 1934 January 11. (Folder 20)
  - "SAP, LKI i Chetvertyi Internatsional," 1934 January 11. Published in International Bulletin of the League of Communist Internationalists Typescript (in Russian), (1934 April). (Folder 21)
  - "Gde granitsy padeniia?" 1934 January 18. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1934 February). (Folder 22)
  - "Die Liga vor der Wendung," 1934 July. Published in Bulletin interieur de la Ligue Communiste Mimeograph copy (in German). Also includes "Die Aufgaben der LKI beim Kampf um die IV Internationale und die Wendung der Stalinisten" (1934 July 21) (Folder 23)
  - "Soviets in America?" 1934 August 17. Published in Liberty, (1935 March 23)
    - Typescript (in English) (Folder 24)
    - Typed copy of article as revised by publishers (in English) (Folder 25)
    - Printed copy (in English, in Liberty, 1935 March 23) (Folder 26)
  - "On the Theses 'Unity and the Youth,'" 1934 December. Published in Bulletin interieur du Groupe Bolchevik-Leniniste (Jeunes) Mimeograph copy (in English), (1934 December 20). (Folder 27)
  - "Obvinitel'nyi akt," 1934 December 30. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescripts (in Russian and French), (1935 January). (Folder 28)
  - "Nekotorye itogi stalinskoi amalgamy," 1935 January 12. Published in La Verite Typescript (in Russian), (1935 January 20). (Folder 29)
  - "Delo Zinov'eva, Kameneva i dr.," 1935 January 18. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1935 February). (Folder 30)
  - "Vse stanovitsia postepenno na svoe mesto," 1935 January 26. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1935 February). (Folder 31)
  - "Rabochee gosudarstvo, termidor i bonapartizm," 1935 February 1. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1935 April). (Folder 32)
  - "Zamechaniia po povodu proekta tezisov Kommunisticheskoi Ligi Iuzhnoi Afriki," 1935 April 20. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1935 July). (Folder 33)
  - "Tsentristskaia alkhimiia ili marksizm?" 1935 April 24. Published in Unser Wort Typescript with handwritten additions (in Russian), (1935 May). (Folder 34)
  - "Za Chetvertyi Internatsional," 1935 July. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 35)
  - "Kak oni pishut istoriiu i biografiiu," 1935 September. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 36)
  - "Ot redaktsii Biulletenia," 1935 September. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 37)
  - "Terror biurokraticheskogo samosokhraneniia," 1935 September 6. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii (1935 September). Printed copy (in English, in New York American, 1936 January 10) (Folder 38)
  - "Po povodu VII Kongressa Kominterna," 1935 September 7. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 39)
  - "Pora organizovat' pomoshch' revoliutsioneram-internatsionalistam!" 1935 September 7. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 40)
  - "Fridrikh Engel's v novykh pis'makh," 1935 October 15. Published in The New International Typescript (in Russian), (1936 June). (Folder 41)
  - "Sektanstvo, tsentrizm i Chetvertyi Internatsional," 1935 October 22. Published in Bulletin de la Ligue des Communistes-Internationalistes (Bolcheviks-Leninistes) Typescript (in Russian), (1935 December). (Folder 42)
  - Preface to Zeller, Fred, The Revolutionary Road for Socialists, Published in 1935. Typescript (in Russian), 1935 November 7. (Folder 43)
  - "Narodnyi front i komitety deistviia," 1935 November 26. Published in La Verite Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 44)
  - Vie de Lenine: Jeunesse, Published in Paris, 1936
    - Typescript with handwritten additions (incomplete, in Russian) (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Notes and working materials (in Russian, French and German). Includes letter by Maurice Parijanine (Folder 2)
  - "Zametki zhurnalista," 1936 January 10. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1936 February). (Folder 3)
  - "Sovetskaia sektsiia Chetvertogo Internatsionala," 1936 January 11. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1936 February). (Folder 4)
  - "Revoliutsionnye plenniki Stalina i mirovoi rabochii klass," 1936 January 15. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1936 February). (Folder 5)
  - "Izmena ispanskoi 'Rabochei Partii Marksistskogo Edinstva,'" 1936 January 22. Published in Unser Wort Typescript (in Russian), (1936 February). (Folder 6)
  - Discussion with Maurice Spector on the American question, Oslo, 1936 February. Published in Writings: Supplement, 1934-40 (New York, Mimeograph copy of transcript (in English), 1979). (Folder 7)
  - "Plan fizicheskogo istrebleniia bol'shevikov-leninistev," 1936 March 25. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1936 May). (Folder 8)
  - "Frantsiia na povorote," 1936 March 28. Published in The New Militant Typescript (in Russian), (1936 April 25-May 9). (Folder 9)
  - Preface to Wohin geht Frankreich? (German edition of Ou va la France?), Published in Antwerp, 1936. Typescript (in Russian), 1936 March 31. (Folder 10)
  - "Tuda, otkuda net vozvrata," 1936 April. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 11)
  - "Novaia konstitutsiia S.S.S.R.," 1936 April 16. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1936 May). (Folder 12)
  - "Po stolbtsam Pravdy," 1936 April 16. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1936 May). (Folder 13)
  - "Samye ostrye bliuda eshche vpered!" 1936 April 17. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1936 May). (Folder 14)
  - "Reshaiushchii etap," 1936 June 5. Published in Unser Wort Typescripts (in Russian and English), and mimeograph copy (in Italian). Latter also includes mimeograph Italian version of "Tasks of the Fourth International" (1936 April 12) (Folder 15)
  - "Frantsuzskaia revoliutsiia nachalas'," 1936 June 9. Published in Unser Wort Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 16)
  - Preface to Ou va la France?, Published in Paris, 1936. Typescript (in Russian), 1936 June 10. (Folder 17)
  - "Maksim Gor'kii," 1936 July 9. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1936 July-August). (Folder 18)
  - "Pered vtorym etapom," 1936 July 9. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), and mimeograph copy (in Italian), (1936 July-August). (Folder 19)
  - Les Crimes de Staline, Published in Paris, 1937. Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 20)
  - "Series of Amalgams," Typescript (in English), 1937. (Folder 21)
  - "Otvety na voprosy redaktsii El Tiempo," Typescript (in Russian), 1937 January 19. (Folder 22)
  - Statement on Moscow Trial charges, 1937 January 23. Published in The Manchester Guardian (1937 January 25). Printed copy (in English, in The Manchester Guardian (Folder 23)
  - Statement on Moscow Trial charges, 1937 January 24. Published in El Nacional (1937 January 25). Printed copy (in English, in The Manchester Guardian, 1937 January 26) (Folder 24)
  - "El proceso de Moscou al dia," 1937 January 25. Published in El Universal Typescript (in Russian), (1937 January 26). (Folder 25)
  - "Vokrug protsessa 17-ti," 1937 January 28. Published in El Universal Typescript (in English), (1937 January 29). (Folder 26)
  - Statement on Moscow Trial charges, 1937 January 31. Published in New York American (1937 February 1). Printed copy (in English, in New York American (Folder 27)
  - "An Incomprehensible Polemical Sally by Mr. Troyanovsky," 1937 February 4. Published in Writings, 1936-37 (New York, Typescript (in English), 1978). (Folder 28)
  - Interview with Mme. Titayna, Coyoacan, 1937 February 11. Published in Paris-Midi Typescript of answers to questions (in English), (1937 February 16). (Folder 29)
  - Answers to questions from Havas correspondent, 1937 February 19. Published in La Lutte ouvriere Typescript (in English), (1937 February 26). (Folder 30)
  - "Kak zhe oktiabr'skoe vosstanie proiskhodilo na dele?" 1937 March 3. Published in The Stalin School of Falsification (New York, Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 31)
  - Preface to The Stalin School of Falsification (English edition of Stalinskaia shkola falsifikatsii), Published in New York, 1937. Typescript (in Russian), 1937 March 3. (Folder 32)
  - "Fenner Brockway, Pritt Number Two," 1937 March 6. Published in Voz Leninista Typescript and mimeograph copy (in English), (1937 April 28). (Folder 33)
  - Statement on Andre Malraux, 1937 March 8. Published in La Lutte ouvriere Mimeograph copy (in English), (1937 April 9). (Folder 34)
  - Deposition on theft of archives in Paris, 1937 March 10. Published in Writings, 1936-37 (New York, Typescript (in English), 1978). (Folder 35)
  - "Otel' Bristol," 1937 March 13. Published in Truth about the Moscow Trials Typescript (in English), (1937 April). (Folder 36)
  - "Some Concrete Questions to Mr. Malraux," 1937 March 13. Published in La Lutte ouvriere Typescript and mimeograph copy (in English), (1937 March 26). (Folder 37)
  - "A Mockery of Justice," 1937 March 16. Published in The Manchester Guardian Typescript (in English) (Folder 38)
  - "The Proposed Barcelona Conference," 1937 March 20. Published in Jiskra Typescripts (in English and French), (1937 June). (Folder 39)
  - Statement on Carleton Beals, 12th session, Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials hearings, Mexico City, 1937 April 17. Published in The Case of Leon Trotsky (New York, Mimeograph copy (in English) (Folder 40)
  - Closing statement, 13th (final) session, Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials hearings, Mexico City, 1937 April 17. Published in The Case of Leon Trotsky (New York, Typescript (in Russian). Includes preliminary draft with letter by Bernard Wolfe indicating corrections (Folder 41)
  - "Vozmozhna li pobeda v Ispanii?" 1937 April 23. Published in Unser Wort Typescripts (in Russian and French), (1937 May). (Folder 42)
  - "Dantsigskii sud nad trotskistami," 1937 April 29. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescripts (in Russian and English), (1937 July-August). (Folder 43)
  - "The Insurrection in Barcelona," 1937 May 12. Published in La Lutte ouvriere Typescript (in English), (1937 June 10). (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - "Mr. Beals as a Witness," 1937 May 18. Published in The New York Times Mimeograph copy (in English), (1937 May 26). (Folder 2)
  - "Stalin o svoikh podlogakh," 1937 June. Published in La Cuarta Internacional Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 3)
  - "Nachalo kontsa," 1937 June 12. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1937 September-October). (Folder 4)
  - "Obezglavenie Krasnoi Armii," 1937 June 15. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1937 July-August). (Folder 5)
  - "Otvety na voprosy Vendelina Tomasa," 1937 July 6. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescripts (in Russian, English, French and German), (1937 July-August). (Folder 6)
  - "Ubiistvo Andreia Nina agentami G.P.U.," 1937 August 8. Published in La Lutte ouvriere Typescript (in English), (1937 August 27). (Folder 7)
  - "Pered novoi mirovoi voinoi," 1937 August 9. Published in La Lutte ouvriere, (1937 August 27)
    - Typescripts (in Russian and English) (Folder 8)
    - Printed copy (in English, in Liberty, 1937 November 13) (Folder 9)
  - "The Examination of Ideas and Individuals through the Experience of the Spanish Revolution," 1937 August 24. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Organizing Committee for the Socialist Party Convention Typescript and typed copy (in English), (1937 October). (Folder 10)
  - "Stalinizm i bolshevizm," 1937 August 29. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in English), (1937 September-October). (Folder 11)
  - "Litsemerie pod maskoi 'bespristrastiia': eshche raz o Fenner Brokvee," 1937 September 5. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescripts (in Russian and English), (1937 September 18). (Folder 12)
  - "Concise Answers to Questions Concerning the Spanish Revolution," 1937 September 14. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Organizing Committee for the Socialist Party Convention Holograph, typescript and mimeograph copy (in English). Also includes mimeograph copies of "The Examination of Ideas and Individuals through the Experience of the Spanish Revolution" (1937 August 24), "On the Sino-Japanese War" (1937 September 23), and "The Ultra-Lefts in General and the Incurable Ultra-Lefts in Particular" (1937 September 28), (1937 October). (Folder 13)
  - Interview with J. P. McKnight, Coyoacan, 1937 September 20. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript of answers to questions (in English). Also includes questions submitted by McKnight, (1937 October 9). (Folder 14)
  - "Tragicheskii urok," 1937 September 21. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in Russian), (1937 November 6). (Folder 15)
  - Answer to question of Selden Rodman, 1937 September 22. Published in Quatrieme Internationale Typescript (in English), (1938 January). (Folder 16)
  - "On the Sino-Japanese War," 1937 September 23. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Organizing Committee for the Socialist Party Convention Typescript (in French), and typed copy (in English), (1937 October). (Folder 17)
  - "Pacifism and China," 1937 September 25. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in English), (1937 October 16). (Folder 18)
  - "The Ultra-Lefts in General and the Incurable Ultra-Lefts in Particular," 1937 September 28. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Organizing Committee for the Socialist Party Convention Typescript (in English), (1937 October). (Folder 19)
  - "Results of the Entry and the Next Tasks," 1937 October 6. Published in Writings, 1936-37 (New York, Typescript (in English), 1978). (Folder 20)
  - Letter to the editor, Modern Monthly, 1937 October 15. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in English). Also includes related letter by Joseph Hansen, (1937 December 11). (Folder 21)
  - Interview with Aftenposten correspondent, Coyoacan, 1937 October 19. Published in Socialist Appeal Typed transcript (in English), (1937 October 30). (Folder 22)
  - Statement on assassination of Ignace Reiss, 1937 October 19. Published in Writings, 1936-37 (New York, Typescript (in English), 1978). (Folder 23)
  - "90 let Kommunisticheskogo manifesta," 1937 October 30. Published as preface to Negentig Jaar van die Kommunist Manifest (Cape Town, Typescripts (in Russian and English) (Folder 24)
  - "Pora pereiti v mezhdunarodnoe nastuplenie protiv stalinizma!" 1937 November 2. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in Russian), (1937 November 20). (Folder 25)
  - "Once Again: The U.S.S.R. and Its Defense," 1937 November 4. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Organizing Committee for the Socialist Party Convention Typescript (in English) (Folder 26)
  - "On the Pioneer Press," 1937 November 29. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in English), (1938 January 1). (Folder 27)
  - Letter to the editor, The New International, 1937 December 15. Published in Writings, 1937-38 (New York, Typescript (in English). Also includes cover letter by Trotsky and related letters by Joseph Hansen and Raya Dunayevskaya, 1976). (Folder 28)
  - "Ispanskii urok: poslednee predosterezhenie," 1937 December 17. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in English), (1938 January 8-15). (Folder 29)
  - "Again Our Attitude on War," 1938 January 2. Published in Bulletin interieur du Parti Socialiste Revolutionnaire adherent au Centre pour la IV Internationale Typescript (in English), (1938 February). (Folder 30)
  - "Za stenami Kremlia," 1938 January 8. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in English). Also includes related letter by Joseph Hansen, (1939 January). (Folder 31)
  - Letter to the editor, El Universal, Typescript (in Spanish), 1938 January 15. (Folder 32)
  - Letter to the editors, De Nieuwe Fakkel and De Internationale, 1938 January 21. Published in De Nieuwe Fakkel Typescript (in English), (1938 February 18). (Folder 33)
  - "A Caricature of Defeatism," 1938 January 26. Published in International Internal Bulletin of the International Secretariat for the Fourth International Typescript (in English), (1938 April). (Folder 34)
  - "The Possibility of Foul Play," 1938 February 18. Published in Socialist Appeal (1938 February 26). Printed copy (in English, in Forward, 1938 March 5) (Folder 35)
  - "Lev Sedov: syn, drug, borets," 1938 February 20. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii (1938 March). Typescript (in Russian), and printed copy (in Spanish, in Hoy, 1938 October 7) (Folder 36)
  - "A Forced Declaration," 1938 February 24. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in English), (1938 March 5). (Folder 37)
  - "Trotsky Sees Trial as Reply to Dewey," 1938 March 2. Published in The New York Times (1938 March 3). Printed copy (in English, in The New York Times (Folder 38)
  - "The Secret Alliance with Germany," 1938 March 3. Published in Writings, 1937-38 (New York, 1976). Typescript (in English), and printed copy of excerpts (in English, in The New York Times, 1938 March 5) (Folder 39)
  - "To the Attention of Thinking People," 1938 March 3. Published in Writings, 1937-38 (New York, Typescript (in English), 1970). (Folder 40)
  - "Trotsky Suggests 4 Knew Too Much," 1938 March 3. Published in The New York Times (1938 March 4). Printed copy (in English, in The New York Times (Folder 41)
  - "Trotsky Sees Army Opposed to Stalin," 1938 March 5. Published in The New York Times (1938 March 7). Printed copy (in English, in The New York Times (Folder 42)
  - "Why Are There So Many Centres? Why Do All Centres Submit to Trotsky?" 1938 March 5. Published in El Universal Typescript (in English), (1938 March 7). (Folder 43)
  - "Rol' Genrikh Iagody," 1938 March 7. Published in The New York Times (1938 March 8). Printed copy (in English, in The New York Times (Folder 44)
  - "Strange New Developments," 1938 March 7. Published in El Universal Typescript (in English), (1938 March 8). (Folder 45)
  - "Anachronisms," 1938 March 8. Published in Excelsior Typescript (in English), (1938 March 9). (Folder 46)
  - "Diplomaticheskie plany Moskvy v zerkale protsessa," 1938 March 8. Published in The New York Times (1938 March 9). Printed copy (in English, in The New York Times (Folder 47)
  - Message to protest meeting, New York City, 1938 March 9. Published in Socialist Appeal Telegram of text (in English), (1938 March 19). (Folder 48)
  - "Podsudimiye Zelenskii i Ivanov," 1938 March 11. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in English), (1938 April). (Folder 49)
  - Letter to the editor, The New York Times, 1938 March 17. Published in The New York Times Typescript (in English), (1938 March 21). (Folder 50)
  - Discussions with Socialist Workers Party leaders, Coyoacan, 1938 March 20-25. Published in Writings, 1937-38 (New York, Typed transcripts (in English), 1976). (Folder 51)
  - "The Problem of the Labor Party," 1938 April. Published in The Labor Party in America (Toronto, Typescript (in English), 1962). (Folder 52)
  - Letter to the editor, Daily Herald (London), 1938 April 22. Published in El Universal Typescript (in English), (1938 April 23). (Folder 53)
  - "Agoniia kapitalizma i zadachi Chetvertogo Internatsionala," 1938 May. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Socialist Workers Party Typescript (in English). Also includes related letter by Raya Dunayevskaya, (1938 April). (Folder 54)
  - Discussion with Socialist Workers Party leaders, Coyoacan, 1938 May 19. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Socialist Workers Party Typed transcript (in English), (1938 June). (Folder 55)
  - "Nado uchit'sia dumat'," 1938 May 20. Published in The New International Mimeograph copy (in German). Also includes mimeograph German version of "Eshche raz o tt. Sneflite i Verekene" (1938 May 23), (1938 July). (Folder 56)
  - "Eshche raz o tt. Sneflite i Verekene," 1938 May 23. Published in Bulletin interieur du Parti Socialiste Revolutionnaire adherent au Centre pour la IV Internationale Typescripts (in Russian and French) (Folder 57)